Alexander Antonison

201 Gillespie Drive Apt 7308 Franklin, TN 37067 https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcp.2010.0016

https://www.linkedin.com/in/AlexanderAntonison

adantonison@gmail.com 256-426-4379 (C)

PROFILE

Senior Data Analyst with 5+ years of experience in providing automated ETL and Reporting solutions with a desire to transition into the field of Data Science using statistical computing to help businesses drive action and gain insights through data. Pursuing an online Masters in Data Science in Fall 2017.

SUMMARY OF SKILLS AND TECHNOLOGIES

SQL Languages: TSQL

Data Environments: Microsoft SQL Server, Salesforce.com

Reporting/ETL: SQL Server Reporting Services (SSRS), Excel

(PowerPivot/PowerQuery/PowerMap), PowerBI, Talend

Scripting Languages: R, Python, PowerShell, BASH

Operating Systems: Windows, Mac, Linux (RedHat, Ubuntu)

Other Technologies: Team Foundation Server, Git, Jira, BitBucket, RStudio, PyCharm, Visual

Studio

WORK EXPERIENCE

Fresenius Rx, Nashville, TN

April 2015 - Present

FreseniusRx is a specialty pharmacy that supports End Stage Renal Disease (ESRD) patients that require dialysis because of kidney failure. I support various analytic groups within FreseniusRx along with day to day operations within FreseniusRx.

Data Analyst II

- Using a combination of Talend and SSRS automated the existing manual reporting which resulted in saving man hours from manually running reports along with increasing the amount of reporting capabilities.
- Utilize TSQL stored procs and functions to more effectively produce and manage reporting and ETL processes.
- Developed a webcrawler in Python that pulled patients Medicare information to facilitate determining a
 patient's pharmacy copay. Developed automated jobs in Talend which pulled patient information from
 SQL as input into the webcrawler and inserted the results back into SQL for reporting and data
 management. Processed 30,000 patients in 4 days with significantly reduced error over the existing
 system.
- Fulfill ad hoc data requests regarding financial, operational, and clinical data using TSQL to write queries to pull data from the Microsoft SQL Server environment.
- Support Salesforce through both developing the TSQL queries to pull the data and use Talend to upsert data into Salesforce.
- Improved existing financial reporting by developing new queries which resulted in more accurate financial reports.
- Assisted in the development of PowerBI dashboards for KPIs surrounding patient population and Sales and Marketing KPIs such as penetration into clinics and enrollments.
- Deliver PowerQuery and PowerPivot Excel files to the business to facilitate more reliable and efficient self-service analytics.
- Use JIRA for managing projects and BitBucket for Source Control.
- Act as senior analyst and provide guidance to fellow analysts regarding pharmacy data such as working with data engineers in developing our data warehouse.

Oilfield Instrumentation (OI), Lafayette, LA

September 2014 – March 2015

Work in the engineering department of an oilfield drilling instrumentation company and responsible for supporting development, testing, and troubleshooting field issues of multiple OI software products.

Systems Analyst

- Upgraded customer's SQL Server Reporting Services (SSRS) reporting system to interface with new reporting software.
 - o Tasks included updating customer's SSRS reports, TSQL stored procedures, functions, tables, and views to work with the new software. Developed additional stored procedures to handle behavioral differences between the various versions of the software.
 - Use Team Foundation Server to source control script files and reports.
- Worked directly with the customer to assess possible software issues and provide technical support.
- Enhanced error handling for PowerShell script that interfaces with an online synchronization service through adding a means of sending an automated e-mail to the customer in the event of an error.
- Produced software bug reports with steps to reproduce, database backup if needed, and guidance from operations on business logic to send to software vendor to improve efficiency in software development.

Wyle, CAS Inc., Huntsville, AL

May 2012 - August 2014

Worked as a black box Software Tester, T-SQL Developer, Systems Engineer, and Data Analyst in support of PATRIOT System Effectiveness Model (PSEM), a simulation model of the PATRIOT missile defense system.

System Analyst

- Developed a suite of TSQL stored procedures and functions that provided a comprehensive evaluation of PSEM's performance in integrated test events. This provided developers, managers, and analysts an efficient means of viewing PSEM's performance and reduced processing time from days to hours.
- Assisted in defining database schema for PSEM 3 which led to improvements in evaluating PSEM's run time performance and fidelity.
- Wrote a BASH script to automate running a model with multiple test cases to support a developer in incremental integration testing of legacy code conversion from FORTRAN to C++.
- Performed Verification and Validation activities on the PSEM, co-authored a report on the findings, and presented results to PATRIOT project office.
- Analyzed PSEM simulation data and assisted software developers in improving model performance which reduced time in finding errors and developing solutions.
- Programmed C# applications to reformat simulation result data to import into Microsoft SQL databases for further analysis. Reduced the time from receiving data to performing analysis from hours to seconds.
- Learned how to use multiple PATRIOT and general Missile Defense analysis software applications to enhance personal ability to analyze data efficiently and aid to other internal groups.

EDUCATION

The University of Alabama in Huntsville, Alabama

Bachelor of Science in Engineering (2007 – 2011) Graduation Date: December 2011

Major: Industrial and Systems Engineering Honors: Magna Cum Laude GPA: 3.52/4.0 (Major: 3.78/4.0)

CERTIFICATES

R Programming from Johns Hopkins University

Coursera Inc. May 2014

https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/DA8G8KC3MT

AWARDS

- Received Wyle CAS Quality Performance Award for V&V Report
- Senior Design Dr. Bob Award Recipient (individual award given to hardest working student)
- Senior Design Team Project Competition winner (Project Manager)